#山东·青岛
Qingdao, Shandong
#这就是炸脂渣最好的原料
This is the best ingredient for fried "Zhi zha" ("fat residual")
#最好的五花肉
Best pork belly
#用五花肉炸脂渣
Cook "Zhi zha" from pork belly?
#最好的五花
Best pork belly
#别的肉也炸不了
You can't use meat from elsewhere for frying
#别的肉它炸出来 肉的色度不好看
If you do, the color wouldn't be nice
#不像这个 这么亮 这么干净
Not like this, so bright, so clean
#大姐这个肉是肥的多 瘦的少吗
Sister, is there more fat than lean meat (in the pork belly that you use)?
#一半一半吧
Half-and-half, I guess
#一半一半
Half-and-half
#我看瘦的占三分之二
I think the lean meat takes up two-thirds
#瘦的占三分之二
The lean meat takes up two-thirds
#这对于平常吃的猪肉来说 肥的已经很多了
Compared with the pork that we usually eat, there's already much fat
#要把它切成这种大细条
You need to cut the meat into such long, thin slices
#每次炸一锅是炸多少斤
How much meat do you fry in one pot each time?
#炸的不少
Quite a lot
#现在大哥是把五花肉放进油锅里
Now the bro is pouring the meat into the pot
#这锅五花肉就开始炸了
And the frying begins!
#我们期待一下吧
I can't wait
#大哥 我问一下 炸这一锅需要多少时间
Bro, may I ask how long it takes to fry each batch?
#一个小时
One hour
#这么长时间
That's a long time
#我看每次炸脂渣都是炸一锅
Every time you fry a whole pot of pork belly
#一炸炸一锅
Yes, one full pot each time
#最开始猪肉是多少斤
How heavy is the pork in the beginning?
#80斤
80 Jin (40 kg)
#炸完之后就剩18斤
After frying, only 18 Jin (9 kg) is left
#最多出18斤
18 Jin at most
#4斤半炸一斤脂渣出来
That's 4.5 Jin of meat for 1 Jin of "Zhi zha"
#生意最好的话 一天1500斤左右
During the busiest times, we fry about 1,500 Jin of pork each day
#现在也就炸500斤
Now 500 Jin at most
#最多的时候 炸1500斤
1,500 Jin when busy?
#最多的时候 外面5个锅
We use five pots outside the shop during the busiest times
#以前是个早市的时候
when we had a morning market here
#一年最忙的时候是什么时候
What time is the busiest for you in a whole year?
#最忙的时候是夏天
Summer
#青岛人愿意喝啤酒 买点脂渣就不用炒菜了
People in Qingdao enjoy drinking beer. They don't need to cook if they buy some "Zhi zha" (as snacks)
#没涨价之前是68元一斤
We sell "Zhi zha" at 68 yuan/jin before the pork price went up
#现在涨了50块钱
Now we have to increase our price by 50 yuan/jin     #这里有一个额外字幕：118元/斤!   118 yuan/jin! 上传的时候补上
#马上 脂渣就会出锅了
The "Zhi zha" will be ready soon
#来 尝尝淡咸
Come on and have a taste!
#越凉越好吃
It's more delicious when cooled down
#来 这是刚炸出来的脂渣
Look. This is the freshly made "Zhi zha"
#大哥说越凉越好吃
The bro said that it tastes better when it's cold
#尝一尝吧 只有一个
Let me have a try. I only have one slice
#哇
Wow
#又脆又硬 脂渣它这个是原味的
Crispy and hard. This is the original flavor
#稍微有点咸味
A little bit salty
#它这种是硬脆 而且带有一定的力度
It's hard and crispy. It holds its shape really well.
#我家的脂渣没有油 把油全炸出来了
My "Zhi zha" doesn't contain much oil. All fat is fried out
#其实咱们吃的大部分东西都是
Acutally the most food that we eat
#加油更好吃
tastes better with oil or fat
#但是像这个猪肉竟然是去掉油
But here, the pork tastes better
#它更的好吃
when all fat is removed
#关 注
#雪 鱼 探 店
Subscribe to "Xue Yu Tan Dian"